## Daniel Martí Casanova

Software Developer

dmarticasanova@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/danielmarticasanova/

+34 667 718 373

Passionate game developer with experience working as a software developer building interactive experiences for museums using game development tools, in computer graphics research and on on various small projects.

Self-motivated, with a good track record of working well with others, and an avid learner. Spanish and Catalan native speaker and proficient in English (C1).

Portfolio: damacaa.github.io

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: C++, C#, .NET (WPF and Forms), Python, JavaScript, SQL.
- Game Development Frameworks/Engines and tools: Unity, Unreal Engine (Blueprints and C++), Godot, Visual Studio
- Development Practices: version control with Git and PlasticSCM, design patterns, SOLID, OOP, DOP.
- Graphics programming: shaders, materials, GLSL, HLSL, OpenGL.
- Game engine programming: component systems, ECS, graphics APIs, physics programming, multi-threading.
- Gameplay programming: gameplay systems and logic, puzzle mechanics, and combat systems.
- Project Management & Collaboration: Agile methodologies, Jira, SCRUM, UML, Trello.
- Graphics & Content Creation Tools: Blender, 3ds Max, Photoshop, Figma.
- Miscellaneous: proven artistic skills (proportion, color, composition...), great communication skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SNGULAR Studios** - Junior Software Developer | Real Time Programmer

MARCH 2023 - PRESENT

- Contributed to real time interactive museum experiences built using game engines like Unity and Unreal.
- Interacted directly with designers to bring their concepts and ideas to life.
- Adapted to evolving project requirements and tight deadlines by implementing code with a focus on reusability and flexibility.
- Developed an internal .NET application that centralizes management and monitoring of interactive museum exhibits.

#### Rey Juan Carlos University, Madrid - Physics Research Assistant

OCTOBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022

- Worked on a state of the art machine learning project.
- Developed an efficient differentiable physics simulation engine in C++ intended for different game engines such as Unity or Unreal.

#### **Personal projects**

Collaborated with teams on various academic projects, work-related tasks, and personal projects. Competed in multiple game jams, where I consistently delivered high-quality projects within deadlines.

- **We're In The Same Boat:** a puzzle game for Android built with Unity and available in the Play Store. I implemented the puzzle logic, as well as a custom clue system using the A\* algorithm.
- Pond Platoon: a browser-based procedural tower defense game built with Unity.
- **Weird Engine:** a custom C++ game engine that I use to learn more about game development, computer graphics and physics simulations..

### **EDUCATION**

# **Rey Juan Carlos University, Madrid** - Bachelor's Degree in Video Game design and development

SEPTEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2022

Obtained multiple distinctions in subjects about OOP in C++ and Javascript, 3D physics simulation, and multiplayer web games using Javascript and Java for backend.

- "Premio extraordinario de fin de carrera": award for the highest GPA among the graduates in the class of 2023.
- Thesis: Framework for inverse animation editing based on differentiable simulation.